Guide to the Frank Cheyne Papé Letters and drawings, ca. 1921-1931
Department of Special Collections
Frank Cheyne Papé Letters and drawings,
ca. 1921-1931
Special Collections M0296
Papé, Frank Cheyne, 1878-
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Norman H. Strouse, 1977.
Biographical Note
British illustrator.
Scope and Content
Letters and invoices (1929-1931) written or directed to Alwyn J. Scheuer. The letters concern orders for illustrations, prices, and shipping. The collection also includes 194 drawings by Papé, illustrations for seven works published between 1921 and 1930.
Container List
- Norman Strouse Gift May, 1977Letters of Frank C. Pape (Box 1)
  Frank Cheyne Pape 1878- Br. illustrator 13 letters and 6 invoices 1929-31 all written or directed to Alwyn J. Scheuer.
  - Letters (All business orders for illus., prices, shipping, also of illustrated books.).
    - 1. 10/1/29Percy House St. John's Rd, Tumbridge Wells. Eng. FCP to AJS 26E 56th St. NYC., ALS 4 p.p. & cvr.
      re: sales and prices of his illustrations and illustrated books.
    - 2. 5/10/30FCP to AJS re: illus., mentions books by Cabell and France., ALS 4 1/2 pp.
    - 3. 11/23/30FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 4 pp & cvr.
    - 4. 12/19/30FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 2 pp. & covr.
    - 5. 1/27/31FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 4 pp. & covr.
    - 6. 4/18/31FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 1 p. & covr.
    - 7. 5/11/31FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 1 p. & covr.
    - 8. 6/1/31FCP to AJS subj: similar, ALS 1 p. & covr.
    - * 9. 7/24/31.Bury House hr. Palborough, Sussex. John Galsworthy to NS., 1 p. ALS & cvr.
      re: ordering Frank Harris books.
    - 10. 7/30/31Tunbridge Wells FCP to AJS, ALS 1 p. & cvr.
    - 11. 9/11/31Tunbridge Wells FCP to AJS, ALS 2pp. & cvr.
    - 12. 9/30/31Tunbridge Wells FCP to AJS, ALS 1 1/2 pp. & cvr.
    - 13. 10/18/31Tunbridge Wells FCP to AJS, ALS 1 p. & cvr.
  - Invoice
    - 1. 12/1/30FCP to AJS A cvr.
    - 2. 4/17/31FCP to AJS ADS rept. of payment for Jurgens bks 2 orig. vignettes for d., 1/2 p.
    - 3. 4/18/31FCP to AJS ADS 1/2 p. invoice for closed vignette for Jurgens.
    - 4. NDFCP to AJS ADS 1/2 rcpt. vignettes for Jurgen, Cream of Jest, & Figures of Earth.
    - 5. NDFCP to [AJS] AD w/ ANS 3/4 p. book price list and note re: Am. ed. Silver Stallion.
    - 6. 4/18/31.FCP to [AJS] ANS 1/2 p. re: returning book.
    - 7. NDFCP to AJS ADS 3/4 p. invoice for colored original - title page Cream of the Jest.
- FRANK PAPÉ ILLUSTRATED BOOKS in the NORMAN H. STROUSE COLLECTION
  - FRANCE, Anatole, Penguin Island. Translated by A.H. Evans With Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. 1st illustrated edition. 4 doublepage endleaves, front and back, 12 full page illustrations, 1 half-title, 1 heading, 8 full page titlepages to Sections, 45 tailpieces, 55 decorated initials. Black cloth binding, gilt-stamped with Papé designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. (1925)
    Only 1 original drawing for this book in the collection - the half-title.
    NO original drawings in the collection for the following three books.
  - FRANCE, Anatole. The Well of St. Claire. Translated by Alfred Allison with Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. 1st illustrated edition. 4 doublepage endleaves, front and back, 12 full page illustrations, numerous tailpieces and decorated initials. Black cloth binding, gilt stamped with Pape designs. Bookplate of Marjorie and H.D. Phillips. London. John Lane Bodley Head. (1928)
  - FRANCE, Anatole. Mother of Pearl. Translated by Frederick Chapmen with Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. 1st illustrated editio 4 double page endleaves, frent and back, 12 full page illustrations, numerous tailpieces and decorated intials. Original dust jacket with Papo designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. (1929)
  - CABELL, James Branch. Domnei, a Comedy of Woman-Worship. Illustrated by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. 1st illustrated edition. With full page black and white illustrations to many chapters as well as the 12 photogravures, 4 double page endleaves front and back. Black cloth binding, gilt stamped with Pape designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. (1930)
    SUMMARY
    The Strouse collection includes (by actual count of the drawings) - 194 original Frank Pape drawings. The detailed descriptions in the following pages show the many repetitions. Also, the artist frequently separated parts of the drawings and used then individually - thus the detail descriptions of the drawings and the actual count of the originals do not make a tally.
    Actual count of original drawings -
    Figures of Earth - 25 original drawings
    Jurgen - 35 original drawings
    Penguin Island - 1 original drawings
    Rabelais - 55 original drawings
    La Reine Pedaque - 33 original drawings
    Revolt of the Angels 22 original drawings
    Thais - 23 original drawings
    Total 194 original drawings
    Dorothy Bevis
    May 20, 1977
- FRANK PAPÉ ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the Norman H. Strouse Collection from Figures OF Earth (Box 2)
  - CABELL, James Branch, Figures of Earth, a Comedy of Appearences. With Illustrations and Decorations by Frank C. Pape. The 5 sections dedicated to Sinclair Lewis, Louis Untermeyer, H.L. Hencken, Hugh Walpole and Joseph Hergesheimer. 8vo, 1st illustrated edition. With 12 full page illustrations, double page decorated endpapers, front and back, 5 decorated full page section heads, 1 heading, 40 decorated chapter initials, and 31 elaborately drawn tailpieces. Black cloth binding, gilt stamped with Pape designs, and original dust jocket with Papé decorations. London. John Lane, Bodley Head. (1925)Bookplate of Marjorie and H.D. Phillips.
    Copy 2 - as above except no dust jacket or bookplate
    - Dom Manueland, Sorceror, Champion, Double, full page
    - What happened..., Full page
    - Manuel, Sorceror, castle, Full page
    - The Two Boys..., Full page
    - I wait for One..., Full page
    - Manuel...modelled..., Full page
    - Alienora and Animals, Full page
    - He was drying out..., Full page
    - This portent..., Full page
    - No witch and werewolf, Full page
    - These magicians..., Full page
    - On most evenings..., Full page
    - Everything was..., Full page
    - Baby in cradle, Full page
    - I am also... Stork retrieving babies, Full page
    - Then Freydis went away.., Full page
    - Horseman and scales, Full page
    - Manuel spent that night., Full page
      Small medallion decoration on titlepage (drawing missing)
    - Bust of Manuel between two pigs., Heading-¼ p.
      Tailpieces
      The book has 31 claboratoly decorated tailpieces varying from 1/8 to 3/4 of a page in size - but NO tailpiece original drawings are included in the collection.
      Colored titlpager(13 3/4 x 9¼ inches) in included in the original drawings but was not used in the book.
      No decorated initials were included with the drawings.
      TOTAL 25 original drawings. The detailed descriptions of the drawings, the repetition, and the separation of parts therefore does not tally with the actual count of the original drawings.
- FRANK PAPE ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the Norman H. Strouse COLLECTION From JURGEN (Box 3)
  - CABELL, James Branch. Jurgen, a Comedy of Justice with Illustrations and DECORATIONS by Frank C. Pape And an Introduction by Hugh Walpole.1st illustrated edition, limited to 3000 copies. With frontispiece in color, 13 full page illustrations, double-page decorated end-papers, front and back, 50 decorated chapter initials, 1 heading, and 46 tail-piece decorations. Black cloth binding, gilt-stamped with Pape designs. Original dust jacket, also decorated. London. John Lane. Bodley Head. 1921.
    Copy 2, exactly as above bat lacking dust jacket. Has Waldo F. Stone bookplate.
    Strouse collection has all original drawings but 1 full page illustration (facing page 10, and these two sped...), lacks 7 tailpieces and all initial drawings.
    - Jurgen rescued to Heaven, Double, full page
    - Dorothy la Desiree', Full page
    - And these two..., Full page
    - Then Jurgen knew..., Full page
    - Jurgen's sword..., Full page
    - Upon the middle..., Full page
    - Jurgen bowed..., Full page
    - So Jurgen sat..., Full page
    - And they all..., Full page
    - And Jurgen civilly, Full page
    - Jurgen spent..., Full page
    - Jurgen clambered..., Full page
    - Every movement..., Full page
    - And so Farewell..., Full page
    - cherub, devil, monk, spilled ink., Heading and side border
    - 50 initials, Decorated initials 1" x3/4"
    - stylized head and snakes, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen and Dame Li, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Damsel on horse, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Centaur, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Dorothy moves toward Dame..., Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen on horse, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Head and snakes (repetition - mi), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen descending, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen in c. ve, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen and Prince fleeing, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shade, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Jurgen and horse jump fence., Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - King, PHILANTHROP, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shade, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Viking ship, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (rep, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Rooster, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Serpent about tree, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (re, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Head, snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Anaitas and sword, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Chloris asleep, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (rep, Tailpiece 1/4 p
    - Beach and seagulls, Tailpiece 1/4 p
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (rep, Tailpiece 1/4 p
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece 1/4 p
    - Cherub, devil, snake, do, Tailpiece 1/4 p
    - Jurgen banished to Hell, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Chrub, devil, snake, dov (rep, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (rep, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Frustrated devils, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Legs, shoes, shadow (rep, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Hearts, flowers, large bi, Tailpiece ½
    - Jurgen on clouds, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Serpent about tree (rep., Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Head and snakes (rep.), Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Floating face, Tailpiece ¼ p.
    - Ruined castle, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Dame Lisa, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Jurgen, Tailpiece ½ p.
    - Explic, Tailpiece
      The Strouse collection has a total of 52 original Frank Papé drawings for Jurgen. Only 7 tailpieces are missing (two are repeated numerous times) and only one full page illustration is lacking.
      TOTAL 35 original 1 drawings. The detailed description of the drawings, their repetition, and the separation of many parts, therefore does not tally with the actual count of the original drawings.
- FRANK PAPÉ ORIGINAL DRAWINGS in the NORMAN H. STROUSE COLLECTION From RABELAIS (Box 4)
  Volume I
  Volume II
  - RABELAIS, Francois. The Complete Works... Being an Account of the Inestimable Life of the Great Gargantua, and of the Heroic Deeds, Sayings, and Marvelous Voyages of Has Son the Good Pantagruel: the Whole Faithfully Rendered into English by Sir Thomas [UNK] and Peter Motteux, with Annotations by Duohat, Ozell, and others.A New Introduction by J. Lewis May, and Many Illustrations by Frank C. Papé. 8vo. 2 vols. Ltd. to 4300 sets. Vol.I has 12 full page illustrations, 1 heading, 1 decorative initial, 2 full page, decorated titlepages to Sections I and II, and 86 tailpieces. Vol. II has 13 full page illustrations, 3 section titlepages, 1 heading, 1 decorated initial, and 144 tailpieces. Black cloth bindings, gilt stamped with Papé designs. London. John Lane. Bodley Head, 1927.
    All full page original drawings are missing from the Strouse collection, The book does not have decorated endleaves but there are two full size original drawings which could have been projected for endleaves and not used in the Volume.
    Prints with checks (Rabelais only) are in our collection
    - Rabelais, book, pen, tankard, 1/8 p.- Heading
    - Small face laughing, 3/4 x ½ - decorated initial
    - Satyr, cherubs, monk and fish, 2 full page titlepages to Books II and III (original drawings missing)
    - rat, human head, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Euses fighting, Apollo, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Teapot breaking on tankard, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Dancing pig, Tailpiece - ¼p.
    - Bacchus in grape tub, Tailpiece - ¼p. (drawing missing)
    - Gargantua in cradle, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Child netting bird, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - cups laughing, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Buckets spilled, bea, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Ride, si sapis, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Devil shovelling people in ov, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Young man looking at pictures, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - oups laughing, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Limp teasing cherub, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Master Janotis and fish, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - dancing grape figures, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Face: leaves, jug, Tailpiece
    - Fish & bottle, Tailpiece
    - Rams & vase, Tailpiece
    - Owl, desk & books, Tailpiece
    - Horse & rider, Tailpiece
    - Copid delivering letter, Tailpiece
    - Cannon firing at head, Tailpiece
    - Sword, Tailpiece
    - Devils carrying corpse, Tailpiece
    - Ships & swans, Tailpiece
    - Sword & helm, Tailpiece
    - Dismembered body, Tailpiece
    - Monk & Demons, Tailpiece
    - Angel & fish, Tailpiece
    - Man drinking, Tailpiece
    - Flying Demon carrying People, Tailpiece
    - Demon with grapes, Tailpiece
    - Legs, imps, Clouds, Tailpiece
    - imp running with herd (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - sly fox (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - Ride, si sapis (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - dancing tankerd (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p. (drawing missing)
    - fish and grapes in shield, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Pantagruel offering fish on platter, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - fish and two legs, Tailpiece - ¼ p. (drawing missing)
    - Pantagruel, rain, fish spout, Tailpiece - 3/4 p. (drawing missing)
    - duck, goose, swan, ships (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - mermaids and fish, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - angel, sword... dum anima..., Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Pantagruel eating people, Tailpiece - 3/4 p. (drawing missing)
    - bowl. of grapes, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Devil shovelling people in oven (rep, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - owt, satyr, grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Ride, si s pis... (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Cannon shoots Pantegruel, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - monk with fish herd, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Friar and animals (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - tankard on drunk figure, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - small devil figures, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - fish driven by imp, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - female in shell, bedecking self, Tailpiece - ½ p. (drawing missing)
    - unicorn nd bird, Tailpiece - ¼ p. (drawing missing)
    - laughing teapot and lady, Tailpiece - 1/8 p. (drawing missing)
    - fish, Tailpiece - 1/8 p. (drawing missing)
    - Rabelais, cornucopia, fish on plat, Tailpiece - 3/4 p. (drawing missing)
      TOTAL original Papé drawings for Rabelais in Strouse collection... Vol. I
      2 large drawings for endleaves (not used)
      1 [UNK]
      1 decorated initial
      59 tailpieces
      Not in collection
      12 full page illustrations
      27 tailpiecos
      2 full page title pages to sections
  - RABELAIS - Volume II - Original Pape Drawings in Strouse Collection (Box 4)
    The 13 full page original drawings are missing from the Strouse collection
    The volume does not have decorated endleaves.
    Two full page titlepages to Sections IV and V are not included. in drawings.
    - Panurge sleeping, 2/8 p, - Heading
    - laughing face, 3/4 x ½ decorated initial
    - imp and shadow, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Friar and wenoh (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Sibyl, fish, frogs. (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - atylized female, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - imp, people on fork (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - 3 faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p/
    - angel rescues people from He (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Devil roasting people (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Devil pouncing on people (re), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Fedallion, Heptune, mermaide, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - dancing tankard (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - fish kissing lady clam (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Friar dandling Pantagruel (two-above(missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - whale swallowing fish, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - stylized grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - fish marries lady clam, Tailpiece - ¼ p
    - Lady decks self in shells (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Devil, females by hair (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Ride, si sapis (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Pedestal, rams dancing (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Bowl of grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p
    - goose swimming (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Devil and cherub, chess (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Baby Bacchus, grape leaves, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Bacchus in grape tub (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - sly fox (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - 3 small faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - stylized jug (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - laughing cups (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - owl, satyr, grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - unicorn chasing bird (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - stylized grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - chcrub, fountain, fish, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - 3 faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Friar and fish (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - fish and jar (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - unicorn, bird (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - courtier on horse (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - ships (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - imp. cherub, satyr, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Devil, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Fish and clam married (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - stylised female (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Friar and wench (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - bird on back, human head, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - cherub and imp ringing bell (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - stylized dancing grapes, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - helmet and sword (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Devil frying people (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - medallion, ship and sea [UNK] (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - devil pouncing on people (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Friar chastising fish (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - bowl of grapes, 2 rams, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - dancing cherubs (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - mermaids (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Devil chasing Panurge (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Devil roasting humans(rep), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - ship, Panurge, mermaid, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - devil abducting man (rep), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - books, scroll, compass (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - bowl of grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - dancing jug (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - drinking face (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - angel, ashcan, rats, devil, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - medallion, mermaid, fish (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - small ships (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - small faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - bird on back, human head (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Pantagruel eats humans, Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - helmet and sword (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - dancing imp (missing), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - cannon firing (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - dancing pig (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Pantagruel's head laughs (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - sword (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - three faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - fish, grapes, shield (rep, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - devil, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - imp, humans on pitchfork, Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - small grapes, Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - cherub ringing bell (rep), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Angels, Pantagruel's legs, imps (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Dum, anima est (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Angels rescue humans from Hell (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Friar, animals, Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Friar and wench (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Kedallion, Neptune, mermaids (rep), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Friar striding thru woods (rep), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Cloves, gauntlets (rep), Tailpiece - ½ p
    - Pantagruel drinks from barrels (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - dancing jug (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - fish, grapes in shield (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - cannon firing (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - mermaid fishing (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - 3 faces (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Panurge fleeing cherub (missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Panurge, cherubs, Friar, fish-jugs. (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - owl at desk (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Devil pouncing on humans (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - imp catching rope (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - imp driving a fish (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Baby Bacchus, leaves (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - imp carrying vegetables (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - fish-headed Friar (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - sly fox (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - sword (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Friar and cherub playing (missing), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Panurge kissing female (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - medallion, sea monster, ship (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - devil's shadow (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - drinking face (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - devil's shadow and imp (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - medallion, Neptune and merma. (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - bee (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - dancing grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Panurge and rainspout (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Frear and animals (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Devil clutches 2 females (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - Panurge, ship, mermaid (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - medallion, mermaid kissing fish (repeat - missing), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - stylized grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - ship (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - dancing jug (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - devil-dragon (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - fountain, cherub, fish (repeat), Tailpiece - 3/4 p.
    - Bacchus in tub (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - stylized drinking head (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/4 p.
    - stylized dancing grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/4 p.
    - stylized grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/4 p.
    - stylized jug (repeat), Tailpiece - ½ p.
    - owl, desk, scroll, books (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - drinking jug (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - 3 jubilant imps (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Baby Bacchus, grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
    - Friar on barrel (missing), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - devil, cornucopia (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - ram (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - small grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - small grapes (repeat), Tailpiece - 1/8 p.
    - Rabelais pointing to open book (missing), Tailpiece - ¼ p.
      TOTAL original Pape drawings for RABELAIS in Strouse collection... VOL. II. The word missing refers only to original drawings. All illustrations are intact in books themselves. Many of the Tailpieces are repeated from Volume I and their original drawings are included with Volume I collection.
      Present for Volume II
      1 original drawing for heading
      1 decorative initial
      106 Tailpieces (38 tailpiece drawings missing)
      13 full page drawings missing
      2 full page title pagedrawings for sections 4 and 5 missing.